A Guide to the Anne Price Yates Papers II, 1898-2005
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Anne Price Yates Papers II, 1898-2005
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2010-065
0.3 cu. ft. 1 box
Collection contains manuscript materials, notes, and correspondence related to Yates' research on the Price family after the publication of her book, Increase in Prices.
Yates, Anne Hayden Price, 1939-
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Anne Price Yates Papers II were donated to Special Collections in 2010.
Biographical Note
Anne Hayden Price Yates, Price family historian, was born in Trenton, New Jersey in 1939, to William Conway Price (born 1906) and Eleanor Franklin Hayden (1908-1973). She married James Stanley Savage and had one daughter, Eleanor. She later married Patrick Audley Yates, with whom she had a son, Adam.
Yates received her education in the American School in Manila, Philippines and earned an associate of arts degree from Florida State University. She later attended the University of Florida. In addition to being the author of Increase in Prices: Some descendants of David and Agnes (Hoffman) Price of 17th century Germany, Yates also compiled and edited The Brothers Conway of Madison County, Virginia: autobiographies of Catlett Conway and William Buchanan Conway and edited Descendants of Edwin Conway, the immigrant, compiled by her father.
Scope and Content Note
The Anne Price Yates Papers II contains manuscript materials, notes, and correspondence related to Yates' research on the Price family after the publication of her book, Increase in Prices. The collection contains correspondence from readers with additional genealogical information on the Price and Harless families, copies of genealogies from the William and Mary Quarterly and Virginia Historical Magazine and more of her own genealogical research. Further correspondence and genealogical material from her father, W.C. Price, is contained in the collection.
Also included is correspondence and a copy of a speech from a ceremony at Virginia Tech honoring Dr. Harvey Black in 1939 while H.L. Price served as Dean of Agriculture, as well as the Virginia Agriculture Experiment Station Bulletins during his tenure. Addtionally, the collection contains two deeds for land transfer between James and Hattie Gibbony and H. L. Price in 1905 and 1908.
Arrangement
The collection is divided into three series: Series I: Anne Price Yates Materials, Series II: William C. Price Materials, and Series III: Harvey Lee Price Materials. The first contains Anne Price Yates' correspondence with readers, arranged chronologically, additional geneological material (undated), and ephemera material (mostly undated). The second series contains the correspondence of W.C. (William C.) Price, arranged chronologically. The third series concerns the papers relating to H.L. (Harvey Lee) Price.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Materials
Anne Price Yates Papers, Ms89-087. Finding aid available on the Virginia Heritage database.
Increase in Prices: Some descendants of David and Agnes (Hoffman) Price of 17th century Germany Spec Genealogy C571.P946 1985
Index Terms
Persons:
Price, Harvey Lee, 1874-1951; Price, William Conway
Subjects:
Blacksburg (Va.); Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Montgomery County (Va.); Virginia Polytechnic Institute
Contents List
- Series I: Anne Price Yates Materials, 1980-2005, n.d.
  - Correspondence, 1980-1989. (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1999. (Box-folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence, 2000-2005. (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence, n.d. (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Genealogical Material from William and Mary Quarterly and Virginia Historical Magazine, n.d. (Box-folder 1-5)
  - Assorted Genealogical Materials, n.d. (Box-folder 1-6)
  - Ephemera, 1929, 1989, n.d. (Box-folder 1-7)
- Series II: William C. Price Materials, 1955-1956, 1985-1989.
  - Correspondence,1955-1956, 1985-1989. (Box-folder 1-8)
- Series III: Harvey Lee Price Materials, 1898-1939.
  - Personal Papers, 1905-1939. (Box-folder 1-9)
  - Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station Brochures, 1898-1910. (Box-folder 1-10)